ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
桃小兔吃冰棒
翻译
磁芯章鱼X
showeryhe
翻译
煮粥达人
电脑团
翻译
静妹粒  累
冬麟
时间轴
chance-coco  兜兜兜爹  念念
电脑狂人
第三季
第五集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
洛克维尔  6英里
穆特尼到此一游
84年到85年
失踪
你见过我吗
-《来车闪》  -《闪电导弹》
- "Dodge 'Em." - "Missile Command."
-《弹弹挖地道》  -《道路杀手》服气吧
- "Dig Dug." - "Grand Prix," Suckers.
戈登  "手"字到你了
Gordon, X to you.
雅达利2600上的游戏
Atari 2600 games.
第一个字必须是前一个游戏的最后一个字
Has to start with the last letter of the previous answer.
《手刃异客》
"Xenophobe."
等等  真的有个叫《手刃异客》的游戏
Wait, wait, there's seriously a game called "Xenophobe"?
对  是砍外星人  不是指排外
Yeah, but you're just being intolerant to aliens, so it's cool.
好了各位  关于交换确认的
All right, guys, any updates on the bug
那个错误我们处理得怎么样了
we've been having with the swap confirmations?
已经彻底排除了  一切顺利
Overhauled and working great.
好了  "核灾小子"正式上黑名单了
That's it, ChernobylBoy is going to the stocks.
-国庆快乐你个混蛋  -好
- Happy Fourth of July, asswipe. - Yeah.
有个菜鸟用户交易了
Some fifth grader reneged
一个《第三类接触》午餐盒然后又反悔了
on a swap for a "Close Encounters" lunch pail.
多次违反交易规则的用户会被取消交易特权
We're revoking trading privileges for repeat offenders.
目前还只是内部测试
It's all internal for now,
但我们正打算加上这一段
but we're working on putting this into here.
让他见识下断头台
Show him the guillotine.
酷  但这意味着你被全网封禁了吗
Awesome but are you dead in Mutiny?
这算是注销用户吗
I mean, are we cancelling people's subscriptions?
就是让你的角色没有脑袋满街走
You just wander around without a head
让大家看见了都知道
and that lets people know
这个无头男是个混蛋
this guy without a head is a total dick.
千万别跟这个混蛋交换
Don't swap with this headless dickwad.
能做个脖子喷血的效果吗
Can we get some blood spurting out of the neck hole?
-我们怎么没想到呢  -快做进去
- God, how did we not think of that? - Put that in, dude! Yes.
好了  我们还要解决区域外交易流程中的
All right, we got to solve for the Sev 1 cache miss bug
一级缓存丢失错误
in the out-of-region swap routine?
今天测试  明天就好
Tests today, ships tomorrow.
-你确定  -戈登  放心吧
- You sure? - Gordo, relax.
跳蚤市场运行良好  唯一没预料到的是
SwapMeet's righteous. The only thing that's sideways
总有人无视"不得买卖"的规则
is people keep ignoring the no buying stuff rule.
好多人都在拿票子买卖
A lot of people are trading for DBs.
-票子  -就是现金
- DBs? - Dollar bills.
技术上我们可以监控每一笔交易
We could technically monitor every trade
完全禁止这种事
to make sure it doesn't happen.
那我可没辙了  这种事可轮不着我拍板
I can't help you there. That's way above my pay grade.
有人拿现金买东西
So people are buying shit for money.
那又怎样  我们早就想到了
So what? We knew this would happen.
太麻烦了  用户想要一种便捷的购买方式
It's clunky. Our users want an easy way to buy things
但是办不到  所以他们很失望
and they're frustrated it doesn't exist.
用户还想让警察乐队复合呢
Our users want the Police to get back together,
可惜人家主唱没兴趣
but Sting's not interested.
道格和克雷格说他们可以利用周末
Doug and Craig said they can spend the weekend
整合他们的代码开通信用卡交易
integrating their code for credit card transactions.
不行
No.
我们收购时他们已进入测试阶段
They were already in beta with it when we acquired them.
基本上可以启用了
It's basically ready to go.
因为他们是从市面上直接拿的
Because they yanked it off the shelf.
那就是信用卡公司提供的示范代码
It's boilerplate code supplied by the credit card company.
他们稍做了美化而已
They just gave it a little shine job.
我们不需要完美的解决方案
We don't need the perfect solution.
要是现在先用上
If we have to temp something in now
以后再自定义也行
and customize it later, fine.
贴创口贴总要好过流血身亡吧
A Band-Aid is better than bleeding to death.
流血身亡
Bleeding to death?
唐娜  跳蚤市场上线后
Donna, SwapMeet has doubled in size
每周规模都会扩大一倍
every week since we went live.
你只是怕速度放缓而已
You're just scared of slowing down.
我不希望增长变慢
I don't want to slow our growth.
而你表现得好像接受信用卡
And you keep acting like accepting credit cards
是一桩魔鬼的交易
is some devil's bargain.
关键在于信用卡使用方便
They make people's lives easier. That's the whole point.
好吧  穆特尼是一座城堡
Okay, Mutiny is a castle.
你和我建好之后分了一点给黛安
You and I built it and then we gave a little piece to Diane.
然后又分了一点给该死的道格和克雷格
And then a little piece to freakin' Doug and Craig.
可是跟信用卡公司做交易
But making deals with credit card companies
就是放下护城河的吊桥
is just lowering the drawbridge.
一个老百姓都没有的王国要城堡有什么用
What good is a castle if nobody's in the kingdom?
别忘了每周规模扩大一倍啊
It doubles in size every week, okay?
肯定有别的解决方案  我保证
There is a fix for this, I promise.
我只是暂时还没有想出来
I just-- I don't know what it is yet.
卡梅  你在下面吗
Hey, Cam, are you down there?
是啊  博斯
Yeah, Bos.
卡梅  我明天早上六点整来接你  好吗
Cam, I'm gonna pick you up tomorrow at 6:00 a.m. sharp, all right?
得早点到机场
We got to get to the terminal a little bit early.
每次他们都为我尾椎骨里的金属棒难为我
They always give me shit about the rods in my tailbone.
好
Okay.
我们搬来时就知道
When we moved here, we knew that
有些情况必须迅速适应
there'd be times that we'd have to adapt quickly.
眼下就是这种情况
This is one of those times.
唐娜  就只有我们  好吧
Donna, we're all alone, okay?
没有别的公司哪怕在尝试做
There's no other company that's even attempting to do
跳蚤市场在做的事
what SwapMeet is doing.
我不想猛地栽进去  一下子把事情搞砸
I don't want to rush in and just screw it up all at once.
能等我周一回来再谈吗
Can we talk about it when I get back Monday?
-什么也不会搞砸  -周一再说
- We're not gonna screw anything-- - Monday.
一路顺风
Have a nice trip.
斯坦福就在墨菲特联邦机场旁边
Stanford's over here right next to Moffett.
再过去是国安重镇
Over here is jackboot central.
国防部  北美联合防空司令部和国安局
DoD, NORAD, the NSA.
我打印了网络上
And I printed out all the directories
所有主机的地址名录
for every mainframe on the network.
我们可以利用我发现的一些弱接入点
And we can leverage some of the weak access points I found.
五角大楼基本上无懈可击
Now, the Pentagon is nearly impenetrable,
但是别的一些地方
but some of these other guys--
犹他州简直就是个筛子
Utah is a total sieve.
这儿是什么
What is this right here?
那不属于阿帕网
That's not really part of ARPANET.
是国家科学基金会
That's just the new network
刚推出的新网络
the National Science Foundation just rolled out.
对  国家科学基金网
Yeah, NSFNET.
史蒂夫·沃尔夫的作品
Steve Wolff's baby.
我通过康奈尔的节点连进去了
I went in through Cornell's node.
它只上线了几天
It's only been live for a couple days.
你能别那样吗
Could you-- could you not do that?
国家科学基金网的传输线
NSFNET's transmission lines
理论上比阿帕网快十倍
are 10 times faster than ARPANET theoretically.
但总是崩溃
But it keeps crashing.
不到一个小时
I've been bumped off
-我就掉线了六次  -还有呢
- six times in less than an hour. - What else?
说真的  乔  那只是一堆拿铁饭碗的蠢蛋
Seriously, Joe, it's just a bunch of tenure-track slapdicks.
他们甚至搞不定基础结构
They can't even get their basic infrastructure right.
他们拿国家网络的补助
They got grants for the national network,
丢一堆钱给地方
threw a bunch of cash at the local level,
让区域网络高不成低不就
and left the regional networks in the middle hanging.
-所以呢  -所以肯定会遭遇瓶颈
- So? - So there's a huge bottleneck baked in.
没空间留给增加的需求
There's no room for increased demand.
-所以像阿帕网  -商用被禁止了
- So like ARPANET-- - Commercial use is banned.
这儿或许有戏可作
There could be something here.
这就是个麻烦
It's a lemon.
我已经研究这个六周了  我知道
I've been working on it for six weeks, I know.
你知道
Well, you know.
你已经研究六周了
You've been working on it for six weeks.
通用原子给我们的资产负债表留下三百万的缺
General Atomics left a hole in our balance sheet $3 million deep.
我们的钱在大量流失  阿帕网就快要被关闭了
We're hemorrhaging money. ARPANET will be mothballed soon.
国家科学基金网就是未来
And NSFNET is the future.
这就是你刚刚告诉我的
That's the story you just told me.
不  乔  听着
No, Joe. Listen--
再继续深挖
Just dig deeper on this.
迁就我吧
Indulge me.
今天就这样了
That's all for today.
睡一觉  莱恩  你脑筋开始不清醒了
Get some sleep, Ryan. You're starting to miss things.
-你来这儿干吗  -我需要跟你谈谈
- What are you doing here? - I need to talk to you.
-不是时候  -就现在
- It's not a good time. - Now.
今天谢谢你了
Thank you for today.
去看这小家伙真让我兴奋
I'm just so excited to see this little monkey,
路过烧烤店都没停
I whizzed right past Sonny Bryan's.
宝宝什么时候开始说话
Hey, when do babies start talking?
三四个月大的时候吧
Um, three or four months?
他说的第一个词会是烧烤
His first words are gonna be barbecue
我会确保的
if I got anything to say about it.
看看这个
Oh, hey, check this out.
记得那个空乘吗  那个有美腿的
Remember that stewardess, the one with the legs?
她给了我这个送萨姆
She gave me that for Sam.
詹姆斯还小的时候  每次我出门旅行
Every time I'd go on a trip when James was young,
我就会弄一个给他  钉在他的泰迪熊上
I'd get one of these, pin it to his teddy bear
这样早上他一睁眼就知道我回家了
first thing in the morning so he'd know I was home.
真是太暖心了  博斯
That's really sweet, Bos.
你怎么计划的  你要把车运回去
So what's the plan? You gonna ship the bike
还是一路开回去
or are you gonna ride off into the sunset,
在回湾区的路上兜一牙的虫子
catch bugs in your teeth on the way back to the Bay?
我都不知道它还能不能骑
You know, I don't even know if it runs.
我想走一步看一步
I'm kind of playing this all by ear.
他们知道你回来了吧
Well, they know you're back, don't they?
不
No.
我不会让我妈有时间准备怎么跟我废话
I'm not gonna give my mom time to work up some stupid speech.
你会庆幸自己来了的
You'll be glad you did this.
你现在挺好  卡梅
You're doing all right, Cam.
真抱歉  我以为琳达不打算离开了
I am so sorry. I thought Linda would never leave.
她该一大早就来接孩子的
She was supposed to pick up the kids first thing in the morning.
对她来说  这就是一大早了
For her, this is first thing.
她告诉我  学校有个猥琐的爸爸
She was telling me about this creepy dad at school
一直叫她一起去卡皮托拉滑滑板
that keeps asking her to go boogie boarding in Capitola.
我觉得她是希望我嫉妒
I think she wants me to be jealous.
我可不喝那玩意装的水
Oh, I am not drinking out of that.
看看这个
Hey, look at this.
记得我们国庆日
Remember that bar we went to
去洋葱谷的路上去的那家酒吧吗
in Independence on our way to Onion Valley?
酒保把我们灌得烂醉  最后不得不睡车里
The bartender got us so drunk, we had to sleep in the car.
没错
Oh, yeah.
丙烷罐放哪了
Hey, where are the propane canisters?
我忘了
I forgot.
但我们可以路上去后院达人买
But we can go stop by Orchard Supply on the way out.
那里独立日不开门
Orchard Supply is not open on the Fourth.
这破玩意根本不能用
You know, and this stupid thing is useless.
我不介意在野外幕天席地
Hey, I don't mind sleeping out under the stars.
响尾蛇就指望你那么做呢
Yeah, that's what the rattlesnakes want you to do.
去还有什么意义
You know, what's the point of even going?
什么都是坏的
You know, nothing's working.
孩子们不在家
Well, the kids are gone
自我们来了加州后
and we haven't had one night alone
就没单独在家度过一个晚上
since we got to California.
我们可以  在家度假
We could always, you know, have a vacation at home.
这样吧
You know what?
我们不去了
We're staying here.
-真的吗  -真的
- Yeah? - Yeah.
我去把牛排解冻
I'm gonna defrost the porterhouses.
你可以把我复活节
You can pull out that lacy thing
买给你的那件肩带蕾丝的衣服找出来
with the straps that I got you for Easter.
我去换运动裤
I am changing into sweatpants.
或是运动裤
Or sweatpants.
看看  我们的发型一样  看到了吗
Look at this. We got the same hair. You see?
你想抱抱他吗
You want to hold him?
不  不了  博斯
No, no, Bos.
-我的出租车就到了  -抱着宝宝
- No, my taxi's coming. - Hold the baby.
抱着宝宝  卡梅伦
Hold the baby, Cameron.
好了
Yeah.
你确定你不能留下来吗  卡梅伦
Are you sure we can't convince you to stay, Cameron?
婴儿床安然到达了
I see the crib got here in one piece.
是啊  其实还是一堆零件
Uh, yeah, in a lot of pieces, actually.
我打算这周末装好
Gonna put it together this weekend.
摇篮已经不够萨姆睡了
Sam's graduating out of his bassinet.
这么快  早熟的小家伙
Already? Precocious little fella.
看看他  我差点忘了
Look at him. Oh, I almost forgot.
记得我以前会给你这个吗
Do you remember when I used to get these for you?
当然记得
Yeah, sure do.
我的车来了  好了
Oh, that's me. Okay.
好  明天一大早见
All right, see you first thing bright and early.
恭喜  你们的宝宝真的很酷
Congratulations. Your baby's really cool.
我也得走了
I got to get going, too.
真不敢相信他们让你国庆节这天上班
I can't believe they're making you work on the Fourth.
总得赚钱养家  工作就是工作
Yeah, well, mouths to feed. Work's work.
我知道那种工作
Oh, I know that kind of work.
我很快就回来
I'll be back soon.
-得去报个到  -好
- Just got to kiss the ring. - All right.
想跟爷爷聊聊吗  过来跟爷爷说说话
Do you want to talk to Grampy? Come talk to Grampy.
今天是国庆节
It's, uh-- it's the Fourth of July.
嗯  你没说今天放假  所以...
Right. I mean, you didn't say I had the day off, so...
莱恩  今天是国庆节
Ryan, it's the Fourth of July.
你要我走吗
So, do you want me to leave?
不
No.
不  进来吧
No, come on in.
要咖啡吗
Coffee?
好
Sure.
关上电脑
Kill the computer.
你喝咖啡什么都不加  对吧
You take it black, right?
加奶油  还有很多糖
Cream, lots of sugar, actually.
喂  是我
Oh, hi, it's me.
我来达拉斯了
I'm here in Dallas.
是啊  我住在汽车旅馆
Yeah, I'm staying at the Motel 6 on...
具体地址我也说不清
I actually don't know where.
附近有迈达斯酒店和沃特伯格汉堡
There's a Midas and a Whataburger.
但是  好吧
But, uh, okay.
我就在这儿
I'm here.
好了  牛排马上就好
All right, steaks will be ready in a few.
我的天
God.
太不真实了
Unreal.
你听见了吗
Do you hear that?
没有
No.
没错
Exactly.
没有发出仓鼠死叫的调制解调器
No modems screeching like a dying hamster.
她可真固执
God, she can be so stubborn.
谁会想到  平时那么随意的人
And, you know, you wouldn't think somebody so punk
对生意上的事会那么保守
would be so conservative when it comes to business.
是啊  我其实指的就是调制解调器
Yeah, I was really just talking about the modem.
当然  我懂  让人压力很大
But, sure, I get it. It's stressful.
但卡梅伦在大多事上都很有帮助
But Cameron's been great for the most part.
孩子们很喜欢她
You know, the kids love her.
不过  这可能好坏参半
Of course, I guess that's a mixed bag.
她对你也很有帮助  对吗
I mean, she makes you better, right?
告诉你  我真的不想谈论工作
You know what? I really don't want to talk about work.
我没谈论工作
I wasn't talking about work.
好吧  我真的不想谈论卡梅伦
Oh, well, I really don't want to talk about Cameron.
那么你想谈点什么呢
Well, what do you want to talk about?
我根本不想说话
I don't really want to talk at all.
然后我们收购了家公司  真叫人抓狂
And then we acquired this company, which was insane
因为一夜之间要发的工资涨了一倍
because our payroll doubled, like, overnight.
倒也没事  因为人们都说
Which is fine because that's what people say
要提高在硅谷的竞争力就得这么做
you have to do to be competitive in Silicon Valley,
所以我们就这么做了
so that's what we did.
对了  我们收购的那家公司
Uh, but, yeah, so the thing that we acquired,
名叫跳蚤市场  是个刚起步的公司
it's called SwapMeet and it started off--
我知道跳蚤市场
I know about SwapMeet.
不可能不知道  因为我还是用户
It's pretty hard to miss 'cause I'm still a subscriber.
-好吧  -是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我差点就买了一台《飞天蜈蚣》街机
I actually almost pulled the trigger on a swap for this "Centipede" cabinet,
但从温尼伯运过来太麻烦
but the shipping from Winnipeg was ridiculous.
再给你们加满吧
Can I refill for y'all?
我不用  你看你
I'm-- I'm okay, but if you...
买单吧
Just the check.
很抱歉我没联系过你
Hey, I'm really sorry that I didn't reach out.
我想写信的  但是
I wanted to write, but I'm--
我不是很善言语
I'm not very good with words
除了程序语言以外
unless it's, like, part of a chunk of code.
老实说  我不确定你希不希望我打给你
And honestly, I wasn't sure if you wanted to hear from me.
我很高兴你打给我
It was good to get your call.
我不是专程来看你的
I mean, I didn't come just to see you.
我是去我妈那儿拿点东西
I came to grab some stuff from my mom.
你要见她啊  那很好  不是吗
Well, you're gonna see her. That's-- that's great, right?
她和伦恩要搬走了
Yeah, I mean, she and Len are moving,
我要去拿件东西
so just got to get what I came here for
然后就撤
and then get the hell out.
我不知道  她
I don't know, she just--
其实我并不想见她  但是
if I had my way, I wouldn't have to see her at all, but...
见到你我真的很高兴
I'm really happy to see you.
别这样  得了吧
Don't. Come on.
你...
I mean, you--
给  要不你来买单
here, why don't you get this
然后卖掉那张你根本没用的机票来抵钱
and start working off that plane ticket that you never used.
开玩笑的  只是个玩笑
I'm kidding. It's just a joke.
我来买单  就三美元的出差经费
I'll get it. It's like a $3 business expense.
我能报销的  没事
I can write it off. It's fine.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
谢谢
Thanks.
新的还没完成他们就过节去了
They quit for the holiday before they finished the new one.
你怎么看
But what do you think?
什么会取代我的广告
What's replacing me?
义齿霜
Denture cream.
彩票
The lottery.
这座城市啊
This city.
我无法确定这里究竟是美丽还是恐怖
I can't decide if it's beautiful or horrifying.
我妈来过这儿
My mom came out here.
又死在这儿
She died here.
什么都在这儿待不长
Nothing lasts in this place.
这座城市在建成初期
The whole city burned down seven times
被烧毁了七次
in the first couple years of its existence.
就连名字也改过
Even its name has been reinvented.
你知道旧金山以前叫什么吗
You know what San Francisco used to be called?
知道  耶尔巴布埃纳
Yeah, Yerba Buena.
这正是这座城市的了不起之处
Look, that's what makes this city so great.
你可以搞砸  你可以失败
You can screw up, you can fail,
那又如何
and so what?
你还有下一次机会
You get another chance.
-有你没你无所谓  -多让人兴奋啊
- It's disposable. - It's exciting.
因为你永远不知道接下来会发生什么
'Cause you never know what the hell's next.
义齿霜
Denture cream.
我不知道我还有没有下一次机会
I'm not sure I've got another next in me.
你得知道这一点
You should know that.
天啊  我好多年没听过这首歌了
Oh, my God. I haven't heard this song in years.
刚刚那火辣的一炮足够把吃的牛排消化掉了吧
Was that totally hot sex worth burning the steaks or what?
好啊  绝对足够了
Oh, God, a billion times yes.
-干杯  -敬这辈子最好的假期
- Cheers. - To the best vacation ever.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love, too.
科学小知识  香蕉皮擦皮鞋效果最好
True fact-- a banana peel will shine your shoes like no other.
年轻的时候可给我省钱了
Saved me a mint in my 20s.
我好像在哪里读到过
Yeah, I think I've read that somewhere.
是吗  他回来了
Oh, you did, huh? Oh, there he is.
我给你
I got a little--
带了点烤肋条和玉米饼
got ribs and hoecake for you.
给你
Um, yeah.
对了  还有
And, oh, there's some--
外边放的烟花
you know, there's some fireworks going on out there
有些还真挺好看的
that are pretty incredible.
他在育儿室里
He's in the nursery.
你爸把婴儿床组装好了  他帮了不少忙
Your dad built the crib. He's been a huge help.
甚至出门买了趟尿布
Even went out for some diapers.
不  我本打算组装婴儿床的
No, no, no. I was gonna build that crib.
再过几小时萨姆就该醒了
Sam will be up in a couple hours.
我赶紧补觉去了
I'm going to bed.
我看咱们都赶紧休息去吧
Well, I think we could all use some sleep.
是啊  好啊  居家好父亲
Yeah. Yeah, okay, Mr. Family Man.
你不在家没人怪你的  詹姆斯
Nobody's blaming you for being gone, James.
也许我该带几个飞行胸章回来  是不是
Well, maybe I should have brought home some pilot wings, huh?
是不是就能弥补了
Maybe that would make up for it.
你小时候很喜欢那些胸章的
You loved those when you were a kid.
你攒了一大盒子呢
Hell, you had a whole box of them.
我攒了一大盒子是因为妈妈是个空姐
Yeah, I had a whole box of them because Mom was a stewardess.
我只是把你给我的往盒子里一扔了事
I just tossed the ones you gave me on top.
你可以篡改过去哄你那个小姑娘老板
You can rewrite history to impress your 15-year-old boss,
但你骗不了我
but you don't fool me.
我们以前去南湾吃的那家餐厅
Hey, what's that place we used to go eat at
叫什么来着
down in the South Bay?
洛斯加托斯餐厅
Oh, Los Gatos Cafe.
-对了  -那儿的火腿蛋松饼太好吃了
- Yeah. - Those eggs Benedict.
我明天带你去那儿吃早午餐
I'm taking you there tomorrow for brunch.
回归麻烦现实前最后再爽一次
One last hurrah before the crazies return.
我们现在的确食欲大开
Well, we definitely worked up an appetite.
天啊  一天两次
God, twice in one day.
我们应该经常这么做
We should do that more often.
一周两次都超过平均水平了
Twice in one week is above average.
杰拉尔德·福特当总统后
We have not had sex
我们就没有一天做过两次了
twice in one day since Gerald Ford was in the office.
-才不是  -就是这样
- No, that's not true. - It's totally true.
生孩子之前  你算算时间线
Pre-kid. Do the math. Carry the one.
是福特时代
Ford.
天啊  我们太需要做爱了
Oh, my God. We really needed this.
幸好没去露营
I'm so glad we didn't go camping.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Really? - Yeah.
很高兴听你这么说
I'm so glad to hear you say that.
是吧
Yeah?
我们没以前那么年轻了
I mean, we're not as young as we used to be.
是啊
Yeah.
但哪怕是年轻时  在树后解手
But, you know, even then popping a squat behind a tree
第二天醒来后的背疼
and your back kills when you wake up.
还是不要了
No, thank you.
是啊  但...
Yeah, but...
你很喜欢去塔玛佩斯山玩的
you loved all those times at Mt. Tam.
什么
What?
约塞米蒂多棒啊
Yosemite was freaking awesome.
知道吗
You know what it is?
这就像疯狂的定义
It's like that saying about what crazy is.
你重复做一件事很多遍
That you do the same thing a ton of times
然后说"这事一直很糟"
and you're like, "This always sucks."
太疯狂了
That's insanity.
一直重复做同样的事
It's doing the same thing over and over
期望会有不同的结果
and expecting a different result.
没错  露营就是疯狂
Yeah. Yes. Camping is insanity.
天啊  我累死了
Oh, God. I am exhausted.
剩下的你要是不吃了
Hell, if you're not gonna eat the rest of the thing,
那就给我
then I want it.
你知道在旧金山湾
You know how hard it is
找到不错的玉米煎饼有多难吗
to get a halfway decent breakfast burrito in the Bay Area?
根本没戏  谢谢
It's a fool's errand. Thank you.
真有趣  我没想到你是在这样的地方长大
It's funny. It's not where I pictured you growing up.
我不是
I didn't.
不是吗
No?
那家伙回来了
Oh, that hombre's back.
他带了现金
He brought cash with him.
你要不要做你来做的事了
You gonna do what you came here for or what?
别说话
Shh, don't.
卡梅伦  我知道头两千英里很容易
Cameron, I know the first 2,000 miles are easy
难在那最后20英尺上
and the last 20 feet are hard,
但你都大老远来了  我们都到了
but you've come all this way and now here we are.
好吧
Okay.
你为自己也该这么做
You owe this to yourself.
也为了他们
And to them.
快点
Come--
他要买走你爸的车了  卡梅伦
he's buying your dad's bike, Cameron.
好啊  别说了
Fine. Just stop talking, okay?
那是你的  快去买下
That's yours. Go get it. Go get it.
行了 你干什么呢
Stop it! What the hell are you doing?
人们犯错从不是因为他们不爱你  卡梅伦
People don't make mistakes because they don't love you, Cameron.
而是因为他们爱你
They make mistakes because they do.
就算你说出来  这也太扯了
Oh, that is such a crock of shit even from you.
你又要我替你收拾烂摊子吗
You want me to pick up the slack for you again?
好啊  今天当然不会有什么不同
Great, why should today be any different, huh?
你够了
Would you stop?
卡梅伦  你不是专程为了车来的
Cameron, you didn't come here just for the bike.
-得了  -老天爷
- Come on, now. - Jesus Christ!
听着  你或许以为自己是我父亲  但你不是
Listen, you might think you're my father, but you're not, okay?
我知道  该死
I know that, God damn it.
不不  我觉得你不知道
No, no, I don't think you do.
我想早点开始今天
Thought I'd get a jump-start on the day.
好啊
Great.
去洛斯加托斯餐厅啊
So Los Gatos Cafe?
我特别想吃那个火腿蛋松饼
I'm really jonesing for that eggs Benedict.
嗯
Yeah.
算了  孩子就要回来了
I don't know. The kids will be home soon.
改日吧
Rain check?
一切都好吗
Everything all right?
嗯
Yeah.
好极了
Everything's fantastic.
我想去鼓捣无线电了  如果你不介意
I'm gonna go work on the ham if it's all the same.
好好玩一会儿
You know, get some good ham time in.
-好啊  -嗯
- Oh, sure. - Yeah.
如果你想吃  冰箱里还有剩披萨
There's some leftover pizza in the fridge if you want some.
老板有消息吗
Any word from the boss man?
她还回来吗  都要中午了
She even coming in? It's already noon.
我们可以往下进行了  只要你一句话
We're ready to move ahead. Just say the word.
我得先跟她商量
I have to talk to her first.
社区现在有人请愿
There's a petition up right now on Community.
叫公元前1986年
It's called 1986 BC.
要求我们让用户支付真钱
It demands we let users pay with actual money.
已经有几百人签字了
Hundreds of people have already signed.
-两小时前发布的  -好吧
- It was posted two hours ago. - Okay, guys.
有个用户刚发电邮给我  感谢穆特尼复兴了
One user just emailed me thanking Mutiny for reviving
"易货制的效率和现代性"
the "efficiency and modernity of the barter system."
他的落款是玛土撒拉[传说很长寿]
He signed it Methuselah.
等等  好吗
Just wait, okay?
我的回答跟一小时前是一样的
My answer is the same as it was an hour ago.
休息一下吧
Take a knee or whatever.
德州怎么样
How was Texas?
还是那么大  宿营怎么样
Still big. How was camp?
-没去  -真棒
- Didn't go. - Peaches.
飞机延误了吗
Was the plane delayed?
早上8点准时到的圣荷西
Got into San Jo' 8:00 a.m. Right on time.
我就是需要休息一上午  我就休了
I just needed a morning, so I took it.
好吧
Okay.
我不知道她在哪  唐娜
Look, I don't know where she is, Donna.
她根本没上飞机
She didn't even get on the damn plane.
你把她留在了德州
You left her in Texas?
我又不负责看着她  唐娜
I'm not her keeper, Donna.
你不知道她在哪吗
And you have no idea where she is?
她住在I30公路的一家旅馆
Kid was at a Motel 6 on I-30.
除此之外  就像我说的
Beyond that, like I said,
德州大得很
it's one big-ass state.
《夜公主》
"Night Princess."
《间谍猎手》
"Spy Hunter."
-《沙士酒保》  -什么
- "Root Beer Tapper." - What?
戈登  科尔克游戏机游戏
Gordo, ColecoVision games.
蠢戈登  该你了
Hey, stupid Gordon, your stupid turn.
"R"到你了
R to you.
不玩
Pass.
戈登闹情绪呢
Gordo's in a mood.
唐娜
Hey, Donna.
旅馆的人说她退房了
The guy at the Motel 6 said she checked out.
要多久
How long will it take?
我们今天可以开始内测
We can start beta tests internally today.
一周内就上线
Be live in under a week.
好  做吧
Okay, then do it.
卡梅伦也同意吗
And Cameron's okay with that?
卡梅伦不在  她会赶上进度的
Cameron's not here. She'll catch up.
乔  看啊  伊萨卡附近有点不对劲
Joe, check this out. Something weird going on near Ithaca.
有些代码片段的特征跟
Found some code fragments with the same fingerprint
IBM  柯达和施乐一样
as IBM, Kodak, Xerox.
乔
Hey, Joe?
嗯
Yeah.
你没事吧
You okay?
好吧  我不知道这究竟是什么
Okay, I don't know exactly what we're looking at here,
但这群傻蛋让位给别人了
but the slapdicks have given way to the big swinging variety
他们在合作一个叫
and they're working on something together
奈瑟网的东西
called NYSERNET.
有意思
That's interesting.
有意思  对
Interesting, yeah,
但还是补不上你担心的那个资金缺口
but it doesn't do much to fill the money hole you're so worried about.
天呐  你干得真棒
God, you're doing great work here.
喂
Hello?
-我找乔·麦克米伦  -我就是
- May I speak with Joe MacMillan? - This is he.
麦克米伦先生  这里是旧金山市诊所
Mr. MacMillan, I'm calling from the San Francisco City Clinic.
现在可以谈谈你最近的来访吗
Is this a good time to discuss your recent visit?
稍等
Hold on one second.
今天就这样吧
We're done for the day.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
麦克米伦先生  你HIV抗体检测的结果出来了
Mr. MacMillan, I have the results of your HIV antibody test.
由于你接触了...
Since you were in contact...
喂
Hello.
我们收购跳蚤市场后
New user sign-ups saw a welcome spike
新用户注册出现了大幅增长
after we integrated SwapMeet,
但现在有太多人抱怨
but we're fielding too many complaints
我们不支持现金业务
about the lack of support for our monetary transactions.
所以今晚  我们将上线信用卡代码
So tonight we will go live with the credit card code
道格和克雷格已经对此进行了一周的测试
that Doug and Craig have been testing all week.
用户进行购买时
When users purchase something,
我们会收取物件本身的售价再加一小笔交易费
we charge them for the item and we add a small transaction fee.
将售价数额的支票寄给卖家
Mail checks to sellers for the sales price--
这是干什么呢
What's this?
首先  欢迎回来
Well, first of all, welcome back.
我想我可以代表大家说一句  很高兴你平安
I think I speak for all of us when I say I'm glad you're okay.
我一直在工作
I've been working.
我们都在工作
We've all been working.
我看出来了
I can see that.
我有交易的解决方案了
I have a solve for transactions.
我们这一周都在进行信用卡界面的内测
We've been in beta on a credit card interface all week.
道格和克雷格的代码吗
Doug and Craig's code?
是的  它很好用
Yeah, it works great.
好吧  那你就没征求我意见决定了
Okay, so you just went ahead and did that without me.
各位能出去一下吗
Could you all excuse us?
我和卡梅伦要单独谈谈
Cameron and I need the room, please.
看看我是不是看懂了
Hey, so let me see if I've got this.
比如说  我想买个...
So let's say I want to buy a,
花一百块买初版《超人》漫画
I don't know, first Superman comic for $100.
穆特尼从我运通卡收费  再加五块
Mutiny charges my AmEx, adds five bucks.
作为交易费
As a transaction fee.
但运通卡会另收三块钱作交易费
But AmEx takes three of those dollars as their transaction fee,
所以穆特尼只挣两块
so Mutiny is only making two bucks.
让我生气的是  昨天
Meanwhile, I'm really pissed because yesterday
我本可拿一百块换本《超人》漫画
I could have shelled out 100 DBs for that Superman
但今天  我要白白花掉五块
and today I'm shelling out an extra five bucks for nothing.
并不是白费  我们提供的是有价值的服务
It's not nothing. We're providing a valuable service.
真像个中间商
Oh, spoken like a true middleman.
好吧  那你想怎么解决
Okay, so what's your solution?
路径号码
Routing numbers.
银行就是用这个转钱
It's how banks move money.
用户用支票支付
And our subscribers pay by checks,
他们的账号本就记录在案
so their account numbers are already on file.
好吧  你卖我《超人》
Okay, you sell me Superman.
穆特尼直接从我的银行提钱
Mutiny pulls funds directly from my bank
将其存入你的账户
and deposits them into your account
用我们自己的路径号码为途径
using our own ABA routing number as a pipeline.
这基本上是免费的
Oh, and it's basically free
因为这不产生交易费
because we don't incur a transaction fee
我们也不收交易费
and we don't charge one either
因为这样成本不会大幅提升
because our expenses haven't skyrocketed.
但如果按你的办法  我们就需要
But then with your way, we'd need, what,
三个人处理信用卡交易
three people handling credit card transactions,
再有几个人处理写支票  寄支票
a few people to handle check writing and mailing,
可能还得找一两个会计
probably an accountant or two.
总共是...
So that's, what...
再雇12个人吗
twelve new hires?
嗯  差不多
Yeah, that's about right.
好吧  我的办法只需要再雇一个
Okay, my way adds one person.
一个
One.
你真是难以置信
I can't believe you.
你也是
Right back at you.
我们说好等我回来再商量的
We agreed to discuss this when I got back.
我们说好周一商量的
We agreed to discuss this on Monday.
今天都周五了  你去哪了
It's Friday. Where have you been?
谁管呢  我这不来了
Who cares? I'm here now.
你凭什么不跟我
Since when do you make decisions
商量一下就为我的公司拿主意
for my company without consulting me?
该死  我想找你商量  但找不到你
God damn it, I tried to consult you and I couldn't find you.
天呐  这就是我一直在担心的事
Oh, my God, this is exactly what I've been worried about.
-什么  -每次有新的人走进门
- What? - Every new person that walks through that door,
穆特尼都会再被从我这儿切走一块
another piece of Mutiny gets cut away from me.
不不  唐娜  穆特尼不仅是我的工作
No, no, no, Donna. Mutiny isn't just my job,
它就是我
it's who I am.
它也是我
It's who I am, too.
我一周都睡不着
I couldn't sleep all week.
我大可无视我收件箱里成山的抱怨
I could ignore the mountain of complaints in my in-box,
但我太在乎了
but I care too much.
我想出了更好的解决办法
I came up with a better solution.
虽然你觉得自己要在这里的一切上
Just because you think you need to sprinkle your fairy dust
洒上自己的仙尘才满意
over everything around here before you feel satisfied
不代表那样就更好
doesn't mean it's better.
不  它就是更好
No, it is better.
天呐
Oh, God.
好吧  但重点不在这里
Okay, but that's not the point.
我们之前有麻烦
We were in real trouble.
我有麻烦时  我环顾四周
And when I'm in trouble and I look around,
得能看到你
I need to find you there.
我们得互相支持
We need to have each other's backs.
有时候我得躲起来  才能理清思路
Sometimes I need to crawl into a hole just find my head.
我知道你一直对我很耐心  哪怕我在拖后腿
I know you're patient with me even when I drag my feet.
我知道我该自己出去找地方住
I know I should find my own place to live
不再给你们添麻烦
and stop imposing on you guys.
我知道
And I know that--
我没去成的那次跟道格和克雷格的晚餐
that dinner with Doug and Craig that I missed
你大概觉得我们不该解雇他们
that you probably didn't think we should fire them,
但你还是替我在黛安面前说话了
but you went to bat for me anyways with Diane.
我知道
I know that.
我是跟汤姆在一起
I was with Tom, okay? That's where I was.
我还想呢
Yeah, I was wondering.
可你总归该打个电话
Still, you should have called.
他说你是我遇到的最好的事
He said that you're the best thing that ever happened to me.
这是真的
And it's true.
并不是因为是他这么说
And not 'cause he said it or anything, just--
你是我的锚
you anchor me.
那我们现在就像个银行了
So I guess we're like a bank now.
这挺酷嘛
That's pretty cool, huh?
就是路径号码
It's a routing number.
我们又不会免费送烤箱
We're not giving away free toasters or anything.
我会支持你的  唐娜
I do have your back, Donna.
我的表现方式很奇怪
I have a weird way of showing it,
但我发誓  真的
but I swear I do.
我也支持你
I have yours.
这是我们唯一的焦点
This and only this is what we focus on.
等等  我觉得这很酷
Okay, yeah, time-out. This is super cool to me,
但只关注国家科学基金网吗
but only NSFNET?
你刚刚扯掉的线  都是大金主
The yarn you just pulled, those are the deep pockets.
没错
Exactly.
这是处女地
It's virgin territory.
沃尔夫创造了一个瓶颈  是吧
Wolff created a bottleneck, right?
是啊  不支持区域网  他是个疯子
Yeah, no support for regional networks. The guy is insane.
他太天才了  他在发出一个信号
The guy is brilliant. He's sending a signal.
他就像我们的戈尔巴乔夫
He's like our Gorbachev.
知道开放政策什么意思吗
Do you know what Glasnost is?
不是伏特加就是卫星
I want to say either a vodka or a satellite.
沃尔夫知道  他的网络若想发展
Wolff knows that the only way his network will grow
就需要私人注资
is if private money gets in the game.
问题是  这现在是违法的
The problem is that's against the law for now.
-但是  -但或许有一日会合法起来
- But... - But maybe one day it won't be.
等法规改变  人们会鱼贯而入
And when the rules change, people are going to flood in.
普通人在家拿苹果电脑  阿米加上网
Average people at home on their Apple IIe and Amiga
这会让系统过载
and it's gonna overload the system.
那么谁来打破瓶颈呢
So who breaks the bottleneck?
我们要在这里
We are going to create
建立一个区域网
a regional network right there.
过去  就是一堆堡垒
The past-- the past is a bunch of fortresses
通通与世隔绝
all closed off from the rest of the world.
我们不用建更快的电脑
We don't have to build a faster computer
或想出下一代必杀应用软件
or dream up the next killer application.
那是你要在堡垒里做的
That's what you do in a fortress.
我们要铺设他们之间的道路
We are going to pave a road between them.
你要要求董事会往一个可能永远
And you're going to ask the board to go deeper in the hole
不会挣钱的项目里投更多钱吗
on something that may never turn a dime?
我才不在乎董事会怎么想
I don't care what the board thinks anymore.
钱只是副作用
Money is just a side effect.
开放政策
Glasnost.
是开放的意思
It means openness.
跟开放作对永远是坏主意
And it's always a bad idea to bet against openness.
-你饿吗  -我不知道  乔
- Are you hungry? - I don't know, Joe.
你不知道自己饿不饿吗
You don't know if you're hungry?
我都不知道该怎么想了
I don't even know what to think anymore.
我想搞清你的思路
I try to decipher your sayings,
但电话一响  你就把我赶去别处了
but then the phone rings and you boot me to another zip code.
我们还没想出要怎么挣钱
And we still haven't figured out how to make any money
每天我回家都晕头转向
and I go home every day and I'm spinning
我都不知道你是不是喜欢我
and I don't even know if you like me.
我简直要疯了
I feel crazy.
你不是要疯了  莱恩
You're not going crazy, Ryan.
你是饿了
You're hungry.
我这周过得很不顺
Look, I've had a tough week.
能跟我一起吃晚餐吗
Will you join me for dinner?
好
Okay.
好  我跟你一起吃晚餐
Okay, I'll come to dinner with you.
挺好的
Sounds nice.
好好看看
Just take a good look.
这就是下一步
That's what's next.
黛安·古德
Diane Gould.
黛安  我是卡梅伦·豪伊
Diane, hi. It's Cameron Howe.
卡梅伦  怎么了
Cameron. What's going on?
我今天早些时候跟唐娜谈过
I had a talk with Donna earlier today
我想打电话
and I wanted to call
跟你说  我知道我最近有些古怪
and say I know I've been a little eccentric lately.
曾有人跟我说  古怪
Someone once told me that eccentric
不过是混蛋的花哨说法
is just a fancy word for asshole.
我也有点古怪
I'm a little eccentric myself.
而且这没办法
And you have to be
作为女人想在这行混出名堂就得这样
if you want to make it as a woman in this business.
路径号码的点子很棒
This routing number thing is really great.
好  我还想说
Yeah, okay, I also just wanted to call
谢谢你
and say thanks for, you know,
能看到穆特尼易物
seeing that Mutiny Exchange
是我们独力做不来的
wasn't something we could do on our own
收购跳蚤市场是明智之举
and that it was smart to buy SwapMeet.
是的  我的确不怎么喜欢道格和克雷格
And, yes, I don't love Doug and Craig,
但我完全尊重你
but I really totally respect
留下他们的决定
your decision to keep them at the company.
我跟唐娜说了
Like I told Donna,
我会愿意付钱赶走他们的  这是做生意的代价
I'd have paid for them to go away. Cost of doing business.
但你决定跟他们合作下去体现了你的坚强
But it shows strength that you decided to make it work.
多谢你打来  但是没这必要
Look, this call is appreciated, but it's unnecessary.
这是你的公司  你不用为自己的决定道歉
It's your company. You don't have to apologize for any decision.
最终  是由你决定
In the end, you decide.
卡梅伦
Cameron?
嗯  谢谢  黛安
Uh, yeah. Okay, thanks, Diane.
我得挂了  再见
I've got to go. Bye.